



+971543407684



nidhi.nair2605@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/nidhinair26



Al Mankhool, Dubai, UAE

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Dental Surgery (B.D.S)

Maharashtra University of Health Sciences



2014-2019 Nashik, India

#### **KEY SKILLS**

#### HARD SKILLS

Oral care (scalingroot planning)
Endodontics
Aesthetics
Dental extractions
Dental prosthesis
Computer skills-MS Word
MS PowerPoint

#### SOFT SKILLS

Efficient
Teamwork
Compassion
Ingenuity
Detail oriented
Active listening
Hardworking
MS Excel

## **LANGUAGES**

**ENGLISH** 

\*\*\*\*

HINDI

\*\*\*\*

**MARATHI** 

\*\*\*\*

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Award for **BEST STUDENT** from the batch 2014-2019 by DEAN (SMBT)

### BEST PAPER PRESENTATION in

Intercollege competition – NAIR Dental College and hospital- 2018

**GENERAL SECRETARY** of the Student Council for the year 2016-2017

# Nidhi Nair

**GENERAL DENTIST** 



## **PROFILE**

I am a compassionate general dentist with 3 years of experience. I am an enthusiastic, hardworking and committed individual. I have strong technical skills, as well as an excellent interpersonal skills. I am eager to be challenged in order to grow and expand on the skillset I have gained through my experience in the healthcare sector.

Currently, I am done with my dataflow process with a positive outcome. I have passed my DHA exam on 13<sup>th</sup> September, 2022 and waiting for my eligibility letter.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### GENERAL DENTIST

Makeover Smile Dental Care by Dr. Tushar Avad

▶ Jan 2020 – July 2022 Full Time Mumbai, India

- Responsible for providing patient care, taking x rays and diagnosing the patient's chief complaints
- Approx. 2-3 root canals done (single sitting, multiple sitting, post and core build up) on daily basis using endo rotary system and apex locators
- Restoration for both anterior and posterior teeth using composite and other materials, application of sealants and fluoride for kids.
- Administered local anaesthesia to almost all my patients undergoing major treatments.
- Extractions of any teeth surgically as well as non-surgically and placement of sutures.
- Other treatments like teeth scaling, prosthesis work like tooth preparation and crown placement, RPD, FPD.
- Assisted my senior for implant placement surgeries (single unit, all on four techniques) for conventional implants as well as basal implants.
- Record and update patient information into clinic database and managed follow ups.
- Participated in camp conducted in schools for routine check-up and to educate the kids about the importance of proper oral hygiene.

#### INTERN

SMBT Dental College, Hospital and Post Graduate Research Centre

▶ Sept 2018- Sept 2019 Full Time Sangamner, India

- One year rotatory internship program in all departments of general dentistry.
- Participated in various camp conducted by college in rural areas, schools and colleges for routine check up and did basic treatments in the mobile dental van.